<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Drake Witt's Homework</title>
        <description>Drake Witt's Homework - Drake Witt</description>
        <link>http://school.drakewitt.com</link>
        <link>http://school.drakewitt.com</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2015-09-18T01:04:27-04:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2015-09-18T01:04:27-04:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>Unit 1 Map</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A map for Unit 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Unit 1 Map&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/embed?mid=zPFhBwC3mfx0.kCBDq6e-fhs8&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://school.drakewitt.com/ap-world/2015/09/18/unit-1-map</link>
                <guid>http://school.drakewitt.com/ap-world/2015/09/18/unit-1-map</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Timeline Project</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The interactive timeline for AP World History. It showcases events and civilizations of the classical and ancient world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#39;//cdn.knightlab.com/libs/timeline3/latest/embed/index.html?source=1_rrOgWdrUfGPSIsayAw6X4CP6o_iElmlvO23_QkY-EE&amp;font=Default&amp;lang=en&amp;initial_zoom=2&amp;height=650&#39; width=&#39;100%&#39; height=&#39;650&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://school.drakewitt.com/ap-world/2015/09/18/timeline-project</link>
                <guid>http://school.drakewitt.com/ap-world/2015/09/18/timeline-project</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Chapter Homework</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Complete notes over the chapters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pages 1 - 14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turned into box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pages 15 - 28&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most Neolithic hunting groups only had 40 to 60 members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agriculture changed the constraints of communities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slash and burn agriculture is where they would burn trees in an area and farm until the soil was depleted and then finding a new area. Humans have only stopped doing this about a 150 years ago.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The advantages of having major permanent settlements were houses built to last, water, and better improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Irrigation was key to farming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trade with nearby hunters was to more so establish peace than to further economic gain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larger cities tend to rule over the smaller cities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a difference between agricultural society and civilization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Around 3500 B.C.E. the first civilization appeared in the middle east.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the next thousand years other started springing up too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A civilization is a society with enough surplus to form divisions of labor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cuneiform was the first form of developed writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This allowed them to organize political structures, send messages, keep records, tax more efficiency, and make contracts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only a minority of people were actually literate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People in civilizations looked down on people not in civilizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Greeks called them &amp;quot;barbarians&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Civilizations also have cons like social structures (i.e. slavery).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Civilizations generated intellectual ability and artists while nomads couldn&amp;#39;t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The greatest achievements of early civilizations were writing, formal code of law, city planning, architecture, institutions of trade, and money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the first civilizations called Mesopotamia was settled in the Tigris and Euphrates river banks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By 4000 BC they were familiar with Bronze and Copper and had already invented the wheel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Sumerians, who had recently invaded the area invented the first alphabet known as cuneiform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only few knew it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Sumerians came up with a number system based on 10, 60, and 360 noscope mlg faze&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Egypt was founded along the Nile River and was less prone to invasions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Pharaoh of Egypt was their king and had a lot of power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hammurabi&amp;#39;s Law Code is equal punishment. You kill somebody you get killed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Egypt lasted until about 1000 BCE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other civilizations popped up along other rivers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technology advanced as they started using coal and iron around 1000 BCE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early civilizations both separated and integrated key groups of people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separate languages and cultures started to form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humans are at every corner of the globe, separated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each civilization had their own approach to foreign policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pages 32 - 54&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The formations of China, India, the Mediterranean, and the Middle East are four large regional civilizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In these areas they had the largest concentration of population.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These civilizations still had connections with nomadic groups, especially for trading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most civilizations did not have borders and developed separately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alexander the Great created a short-lived empire that ranged from the Mediterranean into northwestern India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It combined both cultures which is called syncretism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At around 1000 BCE, the civilizations were a lot bigger than the earlier river valley ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trade links emerged and new services were made such as canals in China or the postal service in Persia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was also a lot of technological change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empires declined and some collapsed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Han dynasty of China, the Gupta in India, and the Roman Empire collapsed around 500 C.E.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The difference in attitudes and cultures can be traced bake to classical civilizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each civilization became more diverse with specific crops for that ecological region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each had its own culture with social structures and other policies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Civilizations would conquer other civilizations and create large empires.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ancient China offered abundant options for talented political advisors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China had rival states operated by nomadic people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confucius undertook a lifelong quest to become the chief advisor to a ruler who possessed the vision and skills to restore centralized control, peace and order in China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confucius&amp;#39; political and social policies became a basic foundation to China, even to this day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confucius advocated rule by a highly educated, exclusively male elite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More ethical than religious system.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stress for respect for elders and male authority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confucius never found the ideal monarch or a suitable post, his students taught his ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rivals of Confucianism is Legalism, Daoism, and Buddhism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is still a major cultural force today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 221 BCE Shi Huangdi&amp;#39;s Qin empire had defeated rivals and founded a new dynasty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shi Huangdi was a tyrant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two peasants who started a revolt and overthrew the dynasty at around 207 BCE, and created the Han empire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Han empire lasted 400 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Han leaders led the most effective bureaucracy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed a &amp;quot;Chinese&amp;quot; identity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its isolation from other cultures allowed them to gain identity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Declining of dynasties didn’t cause chaos like in India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every feature is balanced by an opposite, yin and yang.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An individual should seek a way, called Dao, to relate to this harmony.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Zhou dynasty featured decentralized politics but important cultural innovations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Later dynasties emphasized order and centralization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China is the most connected to its past in today&amp;#39;s society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A family of kings, called a dynasty would start its rule of China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This lasted to the early 20th century.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A dynasty would fade with tax revenue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another dynasty would rise after this or invasion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The three dynastic cycles of classical China are the Zhou, the Qin, and the Han.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Zhou dynasty lasted from 1029 to 258 BCE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It flourished only till about 700 BCE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Zhou did not establish a powerful government.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruling came from alliances with regional princes and nobile families.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Came in from the north and displaced the Shang.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agricultural Kingdoms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rulers couldn&amp;#39;t control their territory directly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Land in exchange for tax and military troops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feudal Period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended territory of China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asserted that heaven had transferred its mandate to rule China to the Zhou emperors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandate of Heaven.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created greater cultural unity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regional rulers formed independent armies, reducing emperors to only a figurehead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Between 402 and 201 BCE was a period known as warring states.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zhou system disintegrated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a span of 35 years a regional ruler set up the Qin Empire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emperor, Shi Huangdi was a brutal ruler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understood the problems in regional aristocrats, and worked hard to undo the force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Powerful armies crushed regional resistance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended Chinese territory and political control to south, present day Hong Kong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In North to protect from invaders, the Great wall was built.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Great Wall spans 3000 miles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Largest construction project in human history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built by forced labor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shi Huangdi ordered a nation census.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standardized units.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Qin dynasty was short lived.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attacks on intellectuals and high taxs to support military.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At emperor&amp;#39;s death, peasants revolted and started a new empire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Han empire formed and lasted 400 years to 220 CE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sought to reduce brutal repression of Qin empire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empanded territory more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trade contracts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most famous ruler, Wu Ti enforced peace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peace brought prosperity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self satisfied tone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confucianism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decline was because of central control weakened, invasions from central Asia, and nomads called the Huns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Between 220 and 589 CE China was in chaos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Qin dynasty stressed central authority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Han expanded the powers of bureaucracy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Largest political system in the classical world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rulers in the Zhou dynasty maintained belief in a god or gods, little attention to nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confucianists did not explicitly seek popular loyalty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mostly accepted by the upper class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daoism was a more elaborate spirituality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;True human understanding comes in withdrawing from the world and contemplating this life form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dao means &amp;quot;the way of nature&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China&amp;#39;s economy featured extensive internal trade and important technological innovations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China&amp;#39;s family system stressed a rigid patriarchy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chinese civilization coordinated many aspects of politics and culture, a key reason that emperors ultimately encourages Confucianism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even family structures were closely related to larger institutions and values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pages 56 - 74&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indian civilization was deeply influenced by geography and climate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Centuries of Aryan invasion and consolidation laid the foundation of classical Indian civilization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;India is separated from Asia by the Himalayas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sumer in India brings large rains called monsoons that are crucial for farming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buddha started Buddhism in India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the Vedic and Epic ages, the Aryan migrants had impacts on culture and social structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alexander the Great invaded India and made contacts with Hellenistic culture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanskrit was the first literary language of the Aryans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They had sacred books called Vedas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rig-Veda, Mahabharata, Ramayana, and Upanishads were the Vedas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Varnas was Aryan social classes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bottom class was untouchables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Untouchables were 5th class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Untouchables were confined to only a few nasty jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Born into caste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Untouchables would transport dead bodies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was believed untouchables would defile anybody from a higher class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indra god of thunder was also god of strength.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two major empires united large parts of India at crucial periods in classical Indian history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A young soldier named Chandragupta Maurya seized power along Ganges River.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First Mauryan dynasty ruler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First rules to unify much of India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;His grandson was Ashoka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even greater figure in India&amp;#39;s history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First served as governor of two providences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converted to Buddhism, seeing in the belief in dharma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dharma is law of moral consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After Ashoka empire started to fall apart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New invaders were the Kushans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kushans pushed into central India from the northwest,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kushan king converted to Buddhism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hurt religion&amp;#39;s popularity by associating it with foreign rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Kushan state collapsed in 220 CE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guptas established a large empire starting 320 CE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negotiate with local princes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This expanded influence without fighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Political stability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not as large of territory as Mauryans did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overturned in 545 CE by nomads called the Huns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network of smaller kingdoms after.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not really instability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local and regional governments dominated in India, which places less emphasis on politics than other early civilizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hinduism and Buddhism were the religions of classical India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the influence of these religious traditions, distinctively Indian arts and sciences developed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because of its extensive trade, India&amp;#39;s artistic and cultural influence reached many parts of the ancient world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The caste system structured India&amp;#39;s social frameowork.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;India developed extensive internal and maritime trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Family life combined patriarchy with an emphasis on affection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China and India offer important contrasts in political emphases, social systems, and cultures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They shared features resulting from the integration of large territories and the use of culture to justify social inequality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pages 76 - 86&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 490 BCE the Greeks defeated a huge Persian army.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fear of the Persians were strong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Greek soldier named Pheidippides ran 26 miles to bring the word to Athens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After delivering it he collapsed and died.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Greeks&amp;#39; had a powerful devotion to the public good of the cities they loved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Persian invasion of Greece began as a punishment for the revolt of several Greek city-states against Persia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persia developed a major empire and cultural tradition. Greek culture reached its height during the 5th century BCE; its influence spread through the empire of Alexander the Great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rome was deeply influenced by Greek tradition as it developed its Republic and its Empire. Greece and Rome were ruled by aristocrats but also introduced some democratic elements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Roman Empire encompassed a huge territory and population.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyrus the Great established a massive Persian Empire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persians developed the religion of Zoroastrianism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Greek City-States developed the Olympic Games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pericles was a famous Greek political figure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peloponnesian Wars was when Sparta and Athens vied for control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phillip II of Macedon conquered the cities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the Hellenistic period, art and culture merged with each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trade flourished.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Little political activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alexandria was in Egypt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Roman republic gradually extended influence around the Italian peninsula.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roman conquest was widespread during the Punic Wars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rome fought the Phoenician city of Carthage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carthage general Hannibal was defeated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Romans spread salt around Carthage to prevent agriculture from growing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guess you could say that….they were salty ayyyy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julius Caesar wan the Civil war between two leaders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Augustus Caesar seized power in 27 BCE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He established basic structure of Roman Empire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peace and prosperity to entire Mediterranean world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conquered France and southern Brittan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slow and decisive fall lasted 250 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invading people from north overtook government in Rome in 476 CE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emperors Diocletian and Constantine tried to reverse falling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constantine in 313 adopted Christianity in an attempt to unite empire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The word for politics comes from the Greek word for city-state polis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct Democracy was created by Greece where people voted directly for laws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most important legislative body was the Senate in Rome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was composed of Aristocrats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two consuls shared primary executive power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Senate could choose dictator in times of crisis.
Each classical civilization emphasized a clear social hierarchy, with substantial distance between elites and the majority of people who did the manual and mental work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pages 87 - 95&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greece and Rome did not generate a major religion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Philosophy, science, and art were the most durable elements of classical Mediterranean culture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greek and Roman economies were based on commercial agriculture, trade, and slavery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The two societies developed somewhat different versions of the patriarchal family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rome began to decline after about 180 CE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It lost territory and suffered economic rivals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The later Roman Empire was periodically invaded and finally collapsed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aristotle was a famous Greek philosopher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoics emphasized a moral independence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Athens, Socrates encouraged his pupils to question conventional wisdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;improvement of the soul&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Athenian government thought he was undermining political loyalty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Socrates was give the options of suicide or exile, he chose the first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trade begins to develop rapidly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong culture emerges, including a rich written language derived from the Phoenician alphabet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formed the Olympic Games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sparta and Athens become two leading city-states&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sparta and Athens cooperate to defeat the huge Persian invasion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highest points 550 - 449 BCE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pericles becomes the most famous political figure in Greece- dominates Athenian politics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plato suggested that human reason could approach an absolute True, Good, and Beauty - which characterized nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Greeks had a interest in rationality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sophocles was a dramatist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are three types of Greek columns; Doric, Ionic, and Corinthian.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They had a concept of afterlife
Classic Greek society had a huge impact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pages 98 - 105&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the classical civilizations involved territorial expansion and related efforts to integrate the new territories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significant civilizations developed in the Americas and Africa outside the immediate classical orbit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nomadic societies played a vital role, particularly in central Asia, in linking and occasionally disrupting classical civilizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The kingdom of Kush was defeated by a rival kingdom called Axum by about 300 BCE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Axum fell to Ethiopia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Sahara was less arid than it is today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Silk Road ranched from Europe to China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shintoism was Japan&amp;#39;s religion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It had a important god of rice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Olmec culture had impressive achievements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teotihuacan was a center of trade and worship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maya was an American civilization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Inca came later.
Polynesian people had reached Fiji and Samoa by 1000 BCE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pages 105 - 119&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was a decline in China and India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A combination of internal weakness and Invasions led to important changes, first in China, then in India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Yellow Turbans were a group of Daoist leaders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Sui dynasty had a brief rule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tang had one of the most glorious periods in Chinese history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rajput controlled small states.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Middle eastern region of Islam became a thing at about 600 CE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allah is their god.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decline in Rome was complex, involving a mix of internal and external factors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The eastern and western portions of the empire developed differently after the fall of Rome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The eastern part later became the Byzantine Empire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Justinian tried to recapture Rome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Augustine was a bishop in northern Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Coptic church in Egypt was big.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The period of classical decline saw the rapid expansion of Buddhism and Christianity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religious change had wider cultural, social, and political implications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bodhisattvas - people could obtain nirvana through meditation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The east Asian form of Buddhism was called Mahayana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul was not a disciple, but an early convert.
Benedict rule in Itally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://school.drakewitt.com/ap-world/2015/09/18/chapter-homework</link>
                <guid>http://school.drakewitt.com/ap-world/2015/09/18/chapter-homework</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
